<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code Nitro</title>
    <link>https://codenitro.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Code Nitro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 18:18:16 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codenitro.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Authentication in .Net Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/post/firebase-auth-asp-dotnet-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 18:18:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/post/firebase-auth-asp-dotnet-core/</guid>
      <description>Firebase is great for inetgrating authentication based on social networks, email or phone number into your client app. Whether you are building a web app or a mobile app, firebase provides one of the easiest ways to authenticate users so that they can login to your applicaiton and access content.
While I was building a mobile app, I was able to setup the client side login flow based on the flutter documentation but could not find much reference about implementing authentication in a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Aseem Gaurav. I am a Software Engineer with 12+ years of experience. I have worked across various This blog is a collction of code snippets, tutorials and learnings that I pick up or have picked up while working on various software systems over the years.
work history   Microsoft Monotype Ion Trading Pitney Bowes - MapInfo  skills   C# .Net, .Net Core Azure  CosmosDB Functions Logic Apps MongoDB Azure Storage Azure Search App Service Event Hub Service Bus Queue   Elastic Search React Redux MobX React Native Flutter Node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
