<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code Nitro</title>
    <link>https://codenitro.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Code Nitro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:56:42 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codenitro.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asp.Net Core WebAPI - New Project</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/post/aspnetcore-in-prod-new-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:56:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/post/aspnetcore-in-prod-new-project/</guid>
      <description>After installing .Net Core Framework, you will be able to run dotnet commands from the command line. To check your installation is working fine, run the version command and it should show the version of .net core installed.
 Open a command prompt window Run the command dotnet --version It will show an output as shown below. The version might differ in your case.  C:\GitHub&amp;gt;dotnet --version 5.0.103 When using vs code, a lot of dotnet functionality will be accessed via the dotnet command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.Net Core WebAPI - Installation and Setup</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/post/aspnetcore-in-prod-installation-and-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 20:18:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/post/aspnetcore-in-prod-installation-and-setup/</guid>
      <description>Below is a list of software and applications we will use throughout this blog series. This post only covers the software needed for the first post. As we move forward, each post will contain information about what to install for that particular section.
Download and Install  VS Code VS Code Extensions  C# for Visual Studio Code (powered by OmniSharp C# IDE Extensions for VSCode Icons for Visual Studio Code   Dotnet Core - Download latest version of .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production Ready Asp.Net Core WebAPI</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/post/aspnetcore-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 13:02:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/post/aspnetcore-in-production/</guid>
      <description>Now that dotnet core version 5 has been available for some time, looking at its progress, adoption and community support, I truly believe that it is ready for prime time. It is one of the best open source frameworks to build all kinds of applications, including web api&amp;rsquo;s or backend services.
There are lots of resources available on building api&amp;rsquo;s with .Net core but very few cover every aspect of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node.js, Express and MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/post/nodejs-express-mongodb-intorduction-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 16:27:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/post/nodejs-express-mongodb-intorduction-course/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS Course - Basics  Node.js is an open-source, cross-platform, back-end JavaScript runtime environment that runs on the Chrome V8 engine and executes JavaScript code outside a web browser. Node.js lets developers use JavaScript to write command line tools and for server-side scripting—running scripts server-side to produce dynamic web page content before the page is sent to the user&amp;rsquo;s web browser. Wikipedia
NodeJS is widely used in building api&amp;rsquo;s and server backend for web and mobile apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firebase Authentication in .Net Core Web API</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/post/firebase-auth-asp-dotnet-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 18:18:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/post/firebase-auth-asp-dotnet-core/</guid>
      <description>Firebase is great for inetgrating authentication based on social networks, email or phone number into your client app. Whether you are building a web app or a mobile app, firebase provides one of the easiest ways to authenticate users so that they can login to your applicaiton and access content.
While I was building a mobile app, I was able to setup the client side login flow based on the flutter documentation but could not find much reference about implementing authentication in a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://codenitro.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>aseem.gaurav@outlook.com (Aseem Gaurav)</author>
      <guid>https://codenitro.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Aseem Gaurav. I am a Software Engineer with 12+ years of experience. I have worked across various This blog is a collction of code snippets, tutorials and learnings that I pick up or have picked up while working on various software systems over the years.
work history   Microsoft Monotype Ion Trading Pitney Bowes - MapInfo  skills   C# .Net, .Net Core Azure  CosmosDB Functions Logic Apps MongoDB Azure Storage Azure Search App Service Event Hub Service Bus Queue   Elastic Search React Redux MobX React Native Flutter Node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
